♪The journey is long, but fearless♪
♪멀리지만 두려움은 없어요♪
♪Yeah soft attachment love♪
♪음 부드러운 애착의 사랑♪
♪Scars will always heal♪
♪상처는 언제나 낫는다♪
♪They will become flowers of time♪
♪그리고 그들은 시간의 꽃으로 변할 것이다♪
♪Someone will give it to you♪
♪누군가가 그것을 당신에게 줄 것입니다♪
♪ Keep going! You won't be alone♪
♪계속하세요! 당신은 혼자가 아닐 거예요♪
♪Conversation with time♪
♪시간과 대화하세요♪
♪Light is your answer♪
♪빛이 답이다♪
♪I hope she is your future♪
♪그녀가 당신의 미래에 있었으면 좋겠어요♪
♪Have tea, family, happiness♪
♪가족과 함께 차를 마시며 행복해요♪
♪There are always regrets in life♪
♪살다보면 후회는 늘 있잖아요♪
♪But you still love♪
♪하지만 당신은 여전히 ​​사랑해요♪
♪Father and winter♪
♪아버지와 겨울♪
[Love is the panacea] [Episode 11]
[사랑은 만병통치약] [11회]
[Works funded by Sichuan Province Major Literary Project in 2022]
[ 2022년 쓰촨성 주요 문학사업 지원 작품 ]
[Adapted from the Ningmeng language novel "Love is the Panacea"]
[닝멍위옌의 소설 '사랑은 만병통치약'을 원작으로 함 ]
very good.
매우 좋은.
We can get up.
우리는 일어날 수 있습니다.
Wei'an.
웨이안.
I want to hug you like this every day.
매일 이렇게 안아주고 싶어요 .
The medical rescue mission is over.
의료 지원 임무가 끝났습니다.
Hospital
병원
Want me back.
내가 돌아오길 원해요.
But I will ask for an extension.
하지만 연장을 요청하겠습니다.
in short,
즉,
Wherever you are I will be there.
나는 당신이 어디에 있든 있을 것입니다.
where are you going?
어디 가세요?
Watch the sunrise.
일출을 감상하세요.
You're angry?
화가 났나요?
In fact,
사실,
Aid missions have no effect on me.
지원 임무는 나에게 아무런 영향을 미치지 않습니다.
As long as I go to the hospital to sign up,
병원에 등록만 하면
They will definitely agree.
그들은 분명히 동의할 것입니다.
I'm not angry.
나는 화를 내지 않습니다.
And you don't have to change anything for me.
그리고 당신은 나를 위해 어떤 변경도 할 필요가 없습니다 .
I don't have any plans,
딱히 계획은 없고,
I just follow where I go.
그리고 나는 내가 가는 곳을 따라갈 뿐입니다.
I don’t even know where I’m going next month.
다음달에는 어디로 갈지도 모르겠어요 .
Then
그 다음에
I will follow you wherever you go.
나는 당신 이 어디로 가든지 당신을 따라갈 것입니다.
I just want to be with you forever.
나는 단지 당신과 영원히 함께하고 싶습니다 .
Is he okay?
그는 잘 지내나요?
How nice.
정말 좋네요.
Wei'an.
웨이안.
I wish to watch
시청하기를 바랍니다
Every sunrise with you
일출마다 너와 함께
the rest of my life.
내 인생의 나머지 부분에 대한.
Then
그 다음에
I will follow you wherever you go.
나는 당신 이 어디로 가든지 당신을 따라갈 것입니다.
I just want to be with you forever.
나는 단지 당신과 영원히 함께하고 싶습니다 .
(Gu Yunzheng.)
(구윤정.)
(I no longer regret it.)
(더 이상 후회는 없습니다.)
(I dare not ask for more.)
(감히 더 이상 요구할 수 없습니다.)
(How long will forever last?)
(영원히 얼마나 오래 지속됩니까?)
(I can't think too far ahead.)
(너무 먼 미래를 생각할 수는 없습니다.)
Wei'an.
웨이안.
If you are tired, take a break.
피곤하면 조금 쉬세요.
[Cidade de Jinhai]
[시다드 드 진하이]
maybe i can't
어쩌면 난 할 수 없을지도 몰라
attend your
당신의 참석
[Box] Eightieth anniversary.
[더박스] 80주년.
But I will send your gift back to China on time.
하지만 당신의 선물을 제 시간에 맞춰 중국으로 보내드리겠습니다 .
Why did you suddenly make such a move?
왜 갑자기 이런 행동을 하는 걸까요?
Do you have a girlfriend?
여자친구가 있나요?
Sim.
심.
we were just together
우리 방금 모였어
And our relationship is not yet stable.
우리 관계는 아직 안정되지 않았어.
So I want to stay here a little longer.
그래서 나는 여기에 더 오래 머물고 싶다.
no problem.
괜찮아요.
You can stay as long as you want.
원하는 만큼 오래 머물 수 있습니다.
I will help you.
내가 당신을 도울 것입니다.
I'm thinking
나는 그것을 생각하고있다
Since you are in love,
당신은 사랑에 빠졌으니까요.
I have to be ready.
준비를 해야 해요.
Which house should I choose for my wedding night?
결혼식 날 밤에는 어느 집을 사용해야 할까요 ?
We have to decorate it.
우리는 그것을 장식해야 할 것입니다.
Grandpa, you are very anxious.
할아버지, 많이 걱정되시네요.
It's still early.
아직 이르다.
Ok, no problem.
알았어, 문제없어.
Yunzheng, lembre-se.
Yunzheng, lembre-se.
Whatever you decide,
당신이 무엇을 결정하든,
I will be your strong support.
여러분의 든든한 버팀목이 되어 드리겠습니다.
Understood.
이해했다.
Okay, I have to hang up.
음, 전화를 끊어야 해요.
I'm going to do ward rounds.
나는 병동을 ​​순회할 것이다.
wedding night...
신혼 여행 밤...
Cefinho.
Chefinho.
I'm going to do ward rounds. Go away.
나는 병동을 ​​순회할 것이다. 비켜가세요.
Stay still.
여전히 유지.
what happened?
무슨 일이에요?
His foot healed overnight.
그의 발은 하룻밤 만에 나았습니다.
He must be crazy.
그는 정말 미쳐가고 있는 게 틀림없어요.
Multiple sclerosis. Sue is amazing.
MS. 수는 놀랍습니다.
【Friendship Hospital】
[우정병원]
Cefinho.
Chefinho.
Not only can you take a scalpel
메스를 잡을 수 있을 뿐만 아니라
But it’s also great with pastry tips.
하지만 페이스트리 팁을 곁들여 도 좋습니다 .
When did you learn this?
언제 이것을 배웠나요?
son.
아들.
Do you like the birthday cake I bought you?
내가 사준 생일 케이크 마음에 들었어 ?
Sim.
심.
I want a toy car
그리고 나는 장난감 자동차를 갖고 싶어
So big.
이 큰.
Okay, I'll buy whatever you want.
알았어, 네가 원하는 건 뭐든지 사줄게.
Yunzheng.
윤정.
grandfather.
할아버지.
You're back.
당신은 돌아왔다.
Yunzheng.
윤정.
Put down your backpack and close your eyes.
배낭을 내려놓고 눈을 감으세요.
I have a surprise for you.
당신을 위한 깜짝 선물이 있습니다.
Close your eyes.
눈을 감 으세요.
hope
희망
Happy birthday.
생일 축하해요.
Do you like this cake?
이 케이크 마음에 드시나요?
Yes, I like it.
네, 좋아요.
Grandpa, how did you know?
할아버지, 어떻게 아셨어요?
Do I like car-shaped cakes?
자동차 모양의 케이크는 어떻게 좋아하나요?
I asked the clerk.
나는 점원에게 물었다.
they said
그들은 말한다
these children
아이들
They love this cake.
그 사람들은 이 케이크를 좋아해요.
real?
진실?
Come.
오다.
Close your eyes and make a wish.
눈을 감고 소원을 빌어보세요.
I hope to see my mother again.
나는 어머니를 다시 만나고 싶습니다.
OK
좋은.
Let's blow out the candles.
촛불을 불어 끄자.
Is he okay?
그는 잘 지내나요?
Sim.
심.
let's go.
갑시다.
one two three.
하나 둘 셋.
state.
봄.
Yunzheng grew up another year.
윤정은 한 살 더 많아졌다.
Let's have cake.
케이크를 먹자.
Sim.
심.
Yunzheng.
윤정.
Grandpa, you should eat first.
할아버지, 먼저 드세요.
How delicious.
정말 맛있어요.
Come.
오다.
tasty?
맛있는?
I'm a little dizzy.
좀 어지러워요.
What did I tell you?
내가 뭐라 말했어?
Grandpa has diabetes and cannot eat cake.
할아버지는 당뇨병이 있어서 케이크를 못 드세요.
Why force him to eat so much?
왜 그에게 그렇게 많은 음식을 먹도록 강요했나요?
He is still a child.
그는 아직 어린 아이입니다.
His mother usually has little control over him
그의 어머니는 대개 그를 거의 통제하지 못합니다.
So he is inevitably selfish and willful.
그래서 그는 필연적으로 이기적이고 자기 의지가 있습니다.
Stop this.
하지마.
Don't go too far.
너무 멀리 가지 마십시오.
I like to eat cake.
나는 케이크 먹는 것을 좋아합니다.
It has nothing to do with Yunzheng.
윤정과는 아무 관련이 없습니다.
Dad, you have ketoacidosis.
아빠, 케톤산증이 있으신가요?
Why do you still need to explain to him?
왜 아직도 그 사람에게 설명하고 있습니까?
Don’t you know how serious the complications are?
합병증이 얼마나 심각한지 모르시나요 ?
Okay, Dad.
알았어, 아빠.
You can't spoil a child like this.
그런 아이를 망칠 수는 없습니다.
This is not good for you.
이것은 당신에게 유리한 것이 아닙니다.
Can I spoil my grandson?
손자를 망칠 수 있습니까?
As much as I want.
내가 원하는 만큼.
Grandpa, are you feeling uncomfortable?
할아버지, 불편하지 않으세요?
Sorry, it's all my fault.
미안해요, 다 제 잘못이에요.
I'm fine. this is normal
괜찮아요. 정상이야
have health problems
건강에 문제가 있다
As we grow older.
나이가 들수록.
This has nothing to do with you.
그것은 당신과 아무 관련이 없습니다.
grandfather.
할아버지.
Actually I don't like eating birthday cake.
사실 저는 생일 케이크를 별로 안 좋아해요 .
I will never eat that again.
나는 다시는 그것을 먹지 않을 것입니다.
How beautiful.
정말 아름다워.
It must be for someone important.
중요한 사람을 위한 것이어야 합니다.
gentlemen.
선생님.
Don't want to take your cake?
케이크를 갖고 싶지 않아?
I have no one to share it with.
공유할 사람이 없어요 .
You can share it with other employees and customers.
다른 직원 및 고객과 공유할 수 있습니다 .
[Wish me a happy birthday. ]
[나의 생일을 축하합니다.]
(Mother.)
(어머니.)
(Finally found someone)
(드디어 누군가를 찾았어요)
(Who can I share the cake with.)
(케이크를 누구와 공유할 수 있나요?)
【Who can I share the cake with. )】
[케이크는 누구랑 나눠먹을 수 있나요?]
[Gu Yunzheng: Wei An. See you on the rooftop at 7pm. Will give you a surprise! ]
[구윤정: 웨이안. 오후 7시에 옥상에서 만나요 . 깜짝 놀라실 거예요!]
What did you say?
뭐라고 하셨나요?
what did you just say?
너 방금 뭐라고 했어?
Gu Yunzheng will not return to China ?
구윤정은 중국으로 돌아가지 않을 것인가?
Why are you so excited?
왜 그렇게 흥분해요?
Of course I'm excited.
물론 나는 흥분된다.
I want to use Gu Yunzheng
Gu Yunzheng을 사용하고 싶었습니다.
Let her return to China.
그녀를 중국으로 돌려보내기 위해.
But now he's here to stay, too.
하지만 이제 그도 남을 것이다.
It all ended up being
이 모든 것은 결국 이렇게 되었습니다.
Shot in the foot.
발에 총을 맞았습니다.
Who fired the shot? Whose feet are those?
누가 총을 쐈나요? 그리고 누구의 발인가요?
you...
너...
my God.
맙소사.
My plan failed.
내 계획은 실패했습니다.
The reason why I brought you together is to reunite you.
내가 당신을 모은 이유는 당신이 다시 모일 수 있도록 하기 위한 것입니다.
Don't stay in Lakaha.
La Caja에 머물지 마세요.
You are not connected either
너도 연결 안 됐어
To someone in Lakaha?
La Caja에 있는 누군가에게?
Stop blaming me.
나를 비난하지 마세요.
Wei'an.
웨이안.
[Gu Yunzheng] But I am very happy for you.
[구윤정] 하지만 당신이 있어서 정말 기뻐요.
You are finally in love.
당신은 마침내 사랑에 빠졌습니다.
And Dr. Gu is such a good person.
그리고 구 박사님은 정말 좋은 분이세요.
I feel much more relaxed
마음이 편해진다
Because he takes care of you
그 사람이 당신을 돌봐주기 때문에
Just like you.
그리고 당신처럼.
tell me now
지금 말해
What did you two do in the desert that night?
그날 밤 사막에서 너희 둘이 무엇을 했는지 .
Want to know?
알고 싶나요?
I won't tell you.
나는 당신에게 말하지 않을 것입니다.
Su Wei'an.
수웨이안.
Why are you like this?
왜 그러세요?
What a heartless person.
참으로 마음이 없는 사람이군요.
I have never avoided you
난 너한테 숨은 적 없어
My love experience.
내 사랑 경험.
Why didn't you tell me?
나한테 말해보는 게 어때?
It's not that I won't tell you.
내가 당신에게 말하지 않겠다는 것이 아닙니다.
It’s just that we haven’t dated yet.
단지 우리가 아직 데이트를 하지 않았다는 것뿐이에요.
Aquele idiota Gu Yunzheng
Aquele 바보 Gu Yunzheng
Haven't confessed his love to you yet ?
아직 그 사람에게 사랑을 고백하지 않았나요?
Sim.
심.
he
그
Confessed his love.
사랑을 고백했습니다.
It's just that I haven't decided yet.
아직 결정하지 못한 것뿐입니다.
Isn't he your idol?
그 사람이 당신의 우상이 아닌가요?
He listens to me.
그는 내 말을 듣는다.
You must take advantage of this opportunity.
기회를 활용해야합니다.
What are you still hesitating about?
아직도 무엇을 망설이고 있나요?
what's wrong with you?
왜 그래?
Your idol likes you
당신의 우상은 당신을 좋아합니다.
But you pretend to be serious.
그런데 당신은 심각한 척 해요.
all good.
문제 없다.
You don't need to consider my feelings.
내 감정을 고려할 필요는 없습니다 .
Laugh if you want.
원한다면 그냥 웃으세요.
I know you want to laugh.
나는 당신이 웃고 싶어한다는 것을 압니다.
he told me
그는 나에게 말했다
Who wants to be with me forever.
나와 영원히 함께 있고 싶어했던 사람.
but i'm not sure
하지만 잘 모르겠어요
If I can make this promise.
내가 이 약속을 할 수 있다면.
Su Wei'an.
수웨이안.
Are you showing off?
당신은 과시하고 있습니까?
I'm really speechless.
정말 말문이 막히네요.
Gu Yunzheng disse
구윤정 디스
Who wants to spend the rest of their lives with you
평생을 당신과 함께하고 싶었던 사람 ,
But you don't agree?
그런데 넌 동의하지 않았어?
if it were me
나라면,
I would marry him immediately.
나는 즉시 그와 결혼할 것이다.
WHO？
WHO?
orchid.
란.
real?
진실?
Hello, Lan.
안녕, 란.
Why are you not sleeping yet?
왜 아직 잠을 자지 않았나요?
Wei'an.
웨이안.
Your aunt is sick.
이모가 아프다.
She went to the hospital.
그녀는 병원에 갔다.
The doctor said
의사가 말했다.
She has a disease called Huntington's disease.
그녀는 헌팅턴병이라는 질병을 앓고 있습니다.
The doctor also said
의사도 그러더군요
The disease is hereditary.
그 질병은 유전된다는 것입니다.
I do not understand.
난 그것을 이해하지 못 했어.
And he said that disease comes in advance.
그리고 그 병이 미리 왔다고 하더군요.
This disease is inherited from the father to the second generation
이 질병은 아버지로부터 2대째까지 유전됩니다.
And it can happen around age thirty.
서른 살쯤 에 발생할 수 있습니다 .
[Disease name: Huntington's disease] Symptoms can be more severe.
[질병명 : 헌팅턴병] 증상이 더욱 심해질 것입니다.
Will you get this disease when you are thirty?
서른 살이 되면 병이 생기나요?
perhaps.
아마.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Wei'an.
웨이안.
Are you listening to me?
내 말을 듣고 있나요?
I don't know if you have time.
시간이 있으신지 모르겠습니다.
can you come back?
돌아올 수 있나요?
Do you want to spend the rest of your life in La Caja ?
남은 생애 동안 La Caja에 머물고 싶습니까 ?
I implore you to think clearly.
명확하게 생각하시길 바랍니다.
How is your research project?
당신의 연구 프로젝트는 어떻습니까?
you will give up
당신은 포기할 것이다
Years of hard work?
수년간의 노력?
Don’t you care about the future of the Chinese people?
Huaren의 미래 에 관심이 없나요?
Think about why you want to study medicine.
왜 의학을 공부하고 싶었는지 생각해 보세요 .
I studied medicine to treat illnesses and save people .
질병을 치료하고 사람을 살리기 위해 의학을 공부했지만 ,
It's not about getting promoted just to write articles
기사를 써서 승진하는 것이 아닙니다 .
I can do that in La Caja.
La Caja에서는 할 수 있어요.
Anyway, I decided to stay in La Caja.
어쨌든 나는 La Caja에 머물기로 결정했습니다.
You can't stop me.
너는 나를 멈출 수 없어.
You're back.
당신은 돌아왔다.
Wei An, what are you doing?
웨이안 씨, 뭐 해요?
where are you going?
어디 가세요?
China.
중국.
China? wait.
중국? 기다리다.
Why did you come back?
왜 다시 오시나요?
Haven't you and Gu Yunzheng started dating now?
당신과 Gu Yunzheng이 이제 함께하기 시작하지 않았나요?
I think about it a lot.
나는 그것에 대해 많이 생각했습니다.
I think I'm not suitable for falling in love
저는 연애하기에는 적합하지 않은 것 같아요.
Making money is more important.
돈을 버는 것이 더 중요합니다.
Su Wei'an.
수웨이안.
Do you want to lie to me again ?
또 나한테 거짓말을 하려는 거야 ?
I'm breaking up with you.
너와는 이제 끝이야.
Wei'an.
웨이안.
What happened to you?
당신에게 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
Did something happen to Lan?
란에게 무슨 일이라도 생긴 걸까요?
No.
아니요.
Su Wei'an.
수웨이안.
Why don't you keep your promise?
왜 말을 지키지 않습니까 ?
Last time you promised not to hide anything from me.
당신은 지난번에 나에게 아무것도 숨기지 않기로 동의했습니다.
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
Jiang.
장.
My aunt suffers from a rare disease.
이모는 희귀병을 앓고 있습니다.
I have to go back now.
이제 돌아가야 해요.
I didn't mean to hide this from you .
나는 일부러 당신에게 이것을 숨기지 않았습니다 .
I don't want anyone to worry about me.
나는 누구도 나에 대해 걱정하는 것을 원하지 않습니다 .
and
그리고
Huntington?
헌팅턴?
how do you know?
어떻게 알 수 있나요?
the day you were stabbed
칼에 찔린 날,
Doctor Gu checked his bag
구 박사님이 가방을 확인했어요
He was examined throughout his body.
그리고 그에게 전신 검사를 해주었습니다.
he won't do that
그 사람은 그러지 않을 텐데
If I didn't suspect that you were seriously ill
그가 당신이 심각하게 아프다고 의심하지 않았다면 .
I am anxious
내가 걱정했다
I checked your bag too.
그리고 네 가방도 확인해 봤어.
I found the genetic test report
유전자 검사 보고서를 찾았어요
Hide it in your notebook.
노트북에 숨겨져 있습니다.
Don't worry, Gu Yunzheng didn't see him.
걱정하지 마세요. Gu Yunzheng은 그를 보지 못했습니다.
Wei'an.
웨이안.
That's why you dropped out of school
그래서 학교를 자퇴한 거야.
Risking your life to make money,
돈을 벌기 위해 목숨을 걸고,
Learned about euthanasia
안락사에 대해 배웠어요
He did not accept Gu Yunzheng.
Gu Yunzheng을 받아들이지 않았습니다.
This is all because
이게 다 이유야
de Huntington.
드 헌팅턴.
Please keep it confidential from me.
이 일은 나에게 비밀로 해주세요 .
do not tell anyone,
아무 한테도 말하지 마세요,
especialmente a Gu Yunzheng.
특히 구윤정.
Could it be?
그럴 수 있을까?
Wei'an.
웨이안.
I think this is impossible.
나는 그것이 가능하다고 생각하지 않습니다.
this is possible
있을 수있다
Is the genetic test report wrong?
유전자 검사 결과가 틀렸다고?
I also hope there is something wrong.
저도 뭔가 잘못됐기를 바랍니다.
I thought as long as I was braver
나는 내가 용감한 한 ,
God will let me go,
신은 나를 놓아주실 것이다.
I will let you love without regrets
후회 없이 사랑에 빠지게 해줄 텐데
It also allows Gu Yunzheng and I to go further.
Gu Yunzheng과 함께 더 나아갈 수 있게 해줄 것입니다 .
But now my aunt is sick.
그런데 지금 이모가 아프다.
Whenever I'm sick,
내가 아플 때마다,
It would be earlier and worse than my aunt's.
이모보다 더 빠르고 더 나쁠 것입니다 .
I can't give it to Gu Yunzheng
구윤정에게 줄 수 없어
What does he want.
그가 원하는 것.
Wei'an.
웨이안.
Stop this.
하지마.
Why is God so unfair?
하나님은 왜 이렇게 불공평하신가?
Because is you?
당신이니까?
soon.
조속히.
all good.
문제 없다.
Wei'an.
웨이안.
Jiang.
장.
I'm very lucky
나는 매우 운이 좋았다
de ter conhecido Gu Yunzheng.
De ter conhecido Gu Yunzheng.
You shouldn't tell him.
그에게 말하면 안 돼요.
He hates irresponsible deserters.
그는 무책임한 탈영병을 싫어합니다.
Let him think I'm a deserter.
내가 탈영병이라고 생각하게 해주세요 .
Then he will forget about me.
그러면 그 사람은 나를 잊어버릴 것이다.
(How beautiful.)
(정말 아름다워.)
(Do you like redwood too?)
(당신도 로즈우드를 좋아하시나요?)
What I want to say is,
내가 말하고자 하는 바는,
You look beautiful like this.
이렇게 보니 예쁘네요.
Drive my car.
내 차를 가져가세요.
I promise to take you anywhere in this city
도시 어느 곳이든 데려가겠다고 약속해요
Fifty minutes later.
50분 안에.
♪I miss you♪
♪보고싶어요♪
♪Can you hear me♪
♪내 말이 들리나요♪
correct.
오른쪽.
I found your motorcycle.
네 오토바이를 찾았어.
I searched all over Lacaha.
나는 La Caja 전역을 수색했습니다.
When I found her,
내가 그녀를 찾았을 때,
It was completely reduced to pieces.
그것은 완전히 조각난 것이었다.
I fixed it part by part.
부분적으로 고쳐봤습니다.
It is now back with its original owner.
이제 원래 주인에게 돌아왔습니다.
hope
희망
I replaced most of the parts
대부분의 부품을 교체했어요
of this motorcycle.
이 오토바이의.
(Then)
(그 다음에)
(She is our joint property.)
(그녀는 우리의 공동 재산입니다.)
(You can use it every day,)
(매일 사용해도 됩니다.)
(but occasionally)
(하지만 가끔)
(can leave with the second owner)
(두 번째 주인과 함께 떠날 수 있습니다)
(Who will be busy with duties.)
(업무로 바쁠 것입니다.)
♪You come back to me♪
♪당신은 나에게 돌아오세요♪
[Su Wei'an]
[쑤웨이안]
sorry.
죄송합니다.
The number you dialed is temporarily unavailable.
귀하가 거신 전화번호는 현재 사용할 수 없습니다.
Please try again later .
나중에 다시 시도해 주세요 .
[Jiang Muying]
[장무잉]
Hello, Doctor. arrive.
안녕하세요, 박사님. 에게.
Alô, Jiang Muying.
알로, 장무잉.
Have you met Su Wei'an?
Su Wei'an을 보셨나요?
Yes, she left Lakaha.
네, 그녀는 La Caja를 떠났습니다.
he left?
그는 떠났다?
I don’t know either, Dr. Gu.
저도 모르겠어요, 구 박사님.
Wei An has always been free and easy.
웨이안은 언제나 자유롭고 캐주얼했습니다.
She can go anywhere she wants.
그녀는 원하는 곳 어디든 갈 수 있습니다.
This is not the first time she has done this.
그녀의 이런 모습은 이번이 처음이 아니다 .
She must have her reasons.
그녀에게는 이유가 있을 것입니다.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Can you help me find a lady?
여자 찾는 걸 도와주실 수 있나요 ?
Her name is Su Weian, Chinese nationality.
그녀의 이름은 중국 국적의 소웨이안(Su Wei'an)입니다.
ladies and gentlemen.
신사숙녀 여러분.
sorry sir.
죄송합니다.
The airport does not provide radio pick-up service.
공항에서는 라디오 픽업 서비스를 제공하지 않습니다.
The plane is about to take off.
비행기가 이륙하려고 합니다.
Please fasten your seat belt.
안전벨트를 매주세요 .
So, what can you do?
그럼 당신은 무엇을 할 수 있나요?
I can check flights for you.
항공편 확인을 도와드릴 수 있습니다.
Where is this lady going?
이 아줌마는 어디로 가는 걸까요?
Where is she going?
그녀는 어디로 가는 걸까요?
ladies and gentlemen.
신사숙녀 여러분.
The plane is about to take off.
비행기가 이륙하려고 합니다.
Where is she going?
그녀는 어디로 가는 걸까요?
Please fasten your seat belt.
안전벨트를 매주세요 .
How do I know where she's going?
그녀가 어디로 가는지 내가 어떻게 알 수 있나요 ?
The plane is about to take off.
비행기가 이륙하려고 합니다.
[Airplane Mode, Vibrate, Restart, Shutdown] Turn off electronic devices.
[비행기 모드, 진동, 재시작, 전원 끄기] 전자 기기를 끄세요.
[Bonito Valley]
[보니토구]
Please turn off electronic devices.
전자 기기를 꺼주세요 .
Hello, the number you dialed is busy.
안녕하세요. 귀하가 전화한 번호는 통화중입니다.
[Press to close]
[끄려면 누르세요]
sorry.
죄송합니다.
The phone you dialed is switched off.
전화하신 전화는 꺼져있습니다.
Please call again later.
나중에 다시 전화해 주세요.
[Cidade de Jinhai]
[시다드 드 진하이]
Tia.
티아.
Wei An, you are back.
웨이안, 돌아왔어.
you are getting more beautiful
점점 예뻐지시네요.
you are still so beautiful
아직도 너무 아름다워
So many years have passed.
이 세월이 흐른 뒤에야.
Wei'an.
웨이안.
Did you have anything to eat on the way?
가는 길에 뭐라도 먹었어?
I'll cook pasta for you.
내가 파스타를 요리해 드릴게요.
no need.
그것은 필요하지 않습니다.
I've eaten on the plane.
나는 비행기에서 먹었다.
Go check out the room.
가서 방을 살펴보세요.
Your mother has been cleaning all day.
네 엄마는 하루 종일 청소하고 정리하고 계셨어 .
Go quickly.
빨리 가세요.
Why don't you put away the book you just read?
방금 읽은 책을 치워두는 게 어때요 ?
How can you be so disorganized?
어떻게 그렇게 무질서할 수 있나요?
Mother.
어머니.
What's this?
그게 뭐였지?
what is that?
저게 뭐에요?
This is fake.
그것은 가짜입니다.
This is just a model.
그것은 단지 모델일 뿐입니다.
Wei'an.
웨이안.
I've told you many times
나는 당신에게 여러 번 말했어요.
Don't leave this thing lying around.
이 일을 방치하지 않도록.
You see, your mother is scared.
봐봐, 네 엄마는 겁이 났어.
How scary.
정말 무서웠어요.
I told you not to clean my room.
내가 방 청소하지 말라고 했잖아 .
You ruined my textbook.
당신이 내 교재를 망가뜨렸어요.
you are not worried
당신은 걱정하지 않습니다
What if your mother had a heart attack?
엄마가 심장마비 걸리면?
You are in such a good mood.
당신은 정말 기분이 좋습니다.
You can still dance in the square for another thirty years
당신은 앞으로 30년 동안 광장에서 춤을 출 수 있습니다.
you only know
당신은 단지 알고
How to refute me.
나를 반박하는 방법.
Come and help me cook.
와서 요리하는 걸 도와주세요.
How scary.
정말 무서웠어요.
Wei An, where are your scissors?
웨이안 씨, 가위는 어디 있어요?
My bangs block my eyes.
앞머리가 눈을 가리네요.
I have to cut it off.
잘라야 해요.
I did not see.
나는 보지 않았다.
Here they come.
여기 있습니다.
They work very well.
그들은 잘 작동합니다.
Mom, these are my surgical scissors,
엄마, 이건 제 수술용 가위 예요
For cutting skin.
피부를 자르는 데 사용됩니다.
They work very well.
그들은 잘 작동합니다.
Just lend it to me.
그냥 나한테 빌려줘
Your fish cutting scissors will work best.
생선 절단 가위가 가장 잘 작동합니다.
You can use those.
그것들을 사용할 수 있습니다.
Does anyone miss me?
나를 그리워하는 사람이 있나요?
Do you want to see me?
당신은 저를보고 싶으십니까?
arrive.
도착.
Are you still looking for information about Huntington?
아직도 헌팅턴 정보를 확인하고 있나요 ?
Sim.
심.
I want to see if there is any new progress in research
연구에 새로운 진전이 있었는지 알고 싶습니다.
In China for the past two years.
지난 2년 동안 중국에서.
You just came back today. Not in a hurry.
오늘 막 돌아오셨어요. 서두르지 않고.
have a good rest.
잘 쉬다.
Sim.
심.
[Clinical Trial Recruitment Announcement]
[ 임상시험 모집공고 ]
Mom, look.
엄마, 보세요.
Zhanghe Hospital has specific medicines for Huntington's disease.
장허 병원에는 헌팅턴병을 위한 특수 의약품이 있습니다.
[A letter to patients with Huntington’s disease]
[ 헌팅턴병 환자들 에게 보내는 편지 ]
Currently undergoing phase III clinical trials
현재 임상 3상 시험 중
and is recruiting research subjects.
연구 대상자를 모집하고 있습니다.
What is a theme?
주제란 무엇입니까?
theme...
주제...
in clinical trials
임상시험 단계에서는
drug development,
약물 개발,
you need to find some people
당신은 사람을 좀 찾아야 해요
Test effectiveness and side effects.
효과 와 부작용을 테스트하기 위해.
Currently, Zhanghe Hospital
현재 장허병원
There's a drug for Huntington's disease
헌팅턴병을 표적으로 하는 약물이 있습니다
They are recruiting subjects.
그리고 대상자를 모집하고 있습니다.
Let's leave Auntie...
이모 떠나자...
It doesn't give.
그것은주지 않습니다.
Do you want your aunt?
이모를 원하시나요?
Become a guinea pig?
기니피그가 되다?
I think it's better to wait
내 생각엔 기다려 보는 게 좋을 것 같아
Until this drug is officially launched.
이 약이 공식적으로 출시될 때까지.
It doesn't give.
그것은주지 않습니다.
No one knows how long it will take
얼마나 걸릴지는 아무도 모릅니다
Enabling the commercialization of drugs .
의약품이 상업적으로 이용 가능하도록 하기 위한 것입니다.
and...
와 함께...
If the situation of aunt
이모의 상태라면
The rate of deterioration is accelerating,
빠른 속도로 악화되고,
The consequences will be...
결과는...
Mother.
어머니.
If no one is willing to try the drug,
아무도 약을 테스트하려고 하지 않는다면 ,
New drugs will never be invented
새로운 약은 절대 발명되지 않는다
Medicine will never advance.
그리고 의학은 결코 발전하지 않을 것입니다.
As long as there is hope,
희망이 있는 한,
We must fight for it.
우리는 그것을 위해 싸워야 합니다.
Sim.
심.
But it's scary enough
하지만 이미 충분히 끔찍해요
Your aunt has this disease.
네 이모가 이 병을 앓고 있기 때문이다.
If this medicine doesn't work,
이 약이 효과가 없으면
we will give you hope
우리는 당신에게 희망을 주었을 것입니다
And brought her down.
그리고 그녀를 환멸시켰습니다.
[Recruitment for clinical trials] [A letter to patients with Huntington’s disease]
[임상시험 모집] [헌팅턴병 환자들에게 보내는 편지]
I'm going to talk to my aunt.
이모랑 얘기 좀 할게.
Well, having hope is better than nothing.
글쎄요, 아무것도 없는 것보다는 희망을 갖는 것이 낫습니다 .
excuse me.
실례합니다.
Can this location be expanded?
이 위치를 확장할 수 있나요?
hope
희망
Even the wipers were on.
심지어 와이퍼도 켜져 있습니다.
He seemed to suddenly lose control.
갑자기 통제력을 잃은 것 같았습니다 .
Possibly myocardial infarction
심근경색일 수도 있어요
Or a sudden cerebral infarction?
아니면 갑작스러운 뇌경색?
Does your father have any medical history?
당신의 아버지는 병력이 있습니까?
No.
아니요.
If it is cerebral infarction or myocardial infarction,
뇌경색 이나 심근경색 이었다면
he'll have every chance
그 사람은 기회가 있을 때마다 있었을 거야
to control the steering wheel.
운전대를 제어할 수 있습니다.
But my father lost control when he was conscious.
하지만 아버지는 의식이 있는 동안 통제 불능 상태였습니다 .
(Dad, what’s wrong with you?)
(아빠, 무슨 일 있어요?)
(What exactly happened at that moment?)
( 그 순간 정확히 무슨 일이 일어났나요?)
[Forensic Pathology Opinion of the Hospital Forensic Medicine Center]
[병원 법의학센터 법병리과의 의견 ]
Eliminate the possibility that my father was a drunk driver from the report
아버지 음주운전 가능성은 신고서에서 삭제
Or a sudden heart attack.
또는 갑작스런 심장 마비를 겪었습니다.
You said your father was conscious but out of control
네 아버지는 의식은 있지만 통제가 불가능하다고 했어
When the accident happened?
사고 당시?
Sim.
심.
I watch the camera carefully.
나는 카메라를 주의 깊게 관찰했다.
very light,
굉장히 가벼웠고,
But I can see my dad is struggling
하지만 아버지가 힘들어하고 계시다는 걸 알 수 있었어요
And there was no physical reaction.
물리적으로 반응하지 않았습니다.
Has your father done anything noteworthy lately?
당신의 아버지가 최근에 눈에 띄는 행동을 취하셨나요 ?
Obviously abnormal.
명백한 변칙.
Any unusual circumstances within these three months.
이 3개월 동안 어떤 이상이 있었나요?
He is under great pressure
그는 스트레스를 받는다
And it’s easy to lose patience.
그리고 쉽게 인내심을 잃습니다.
Does this count?
그게 중요합니까?
what else?
또 뭐야?
My father fell easily even on flat ground.
아버지는 평지에서도 넘어지는 경향이 있습니다.
Your father's abnormality
네 아버지의 변칙
This may be a neurological disorder.
아마도 신경학적 장애일 가능성이 높습니다.
If you want to know the reason
원인을 알고 싶다면,
I recommend
제안합니다
Get genetic testing.
유전자 검사를 받아보세요.
(Your genetic report shows
(귀하의 유전 보고서에 따르면
(This is the number of cytosine adenine trinucleotide repeats)
(사이토신 아데닌 트리뉴클레오티드 반복 수 )
(and guanine in the IT15 gene)
(그리고 IT15 유전자의 구아닌)
(Already over forty)
(40보다 큽니다.)
(Above normal range.)
(정상범위를 넘어섰습니다.)
(You carry the gene that causes Huntington’s disease.)
(당신은 헌팅턴병을 일으키는 유전자를 가지고 있습니다 .)
(If the condition develops in the future,)
(향후 질병이 발생할 경우)
(You may not have control over your members)
(귀하는 회원을 통제할 수 없습니다 )
(And it's hard to pick up a scalpel.)
(그리고 메스를 집는 것도 어려울 것입니다.)
[Huaren Medical University] [Study diligently and seek truth].
[화인의과대학] [진리를 위한 부지런한 배움].
Wei'an
웨이안
Today I officially become a medical student.
오늘 공식적으로 의과대학생이 되었습니다 .
I will try to become a doctor.
나는 의사가 되기 위해 열심히 노력할 것이다 .
let's go.
갑시다.
Study hard and work hard.
열심히 공부하고 열심히 일하세요.
Let’s take a group photo today to celebrate.
오늘을 축하하기 위해 단체 사진을 찍자 .
[Wen Ran]
[웬란]
(Wen Ran.)
(웬 란.)
(Your father’s research on HDQ39)
(HDQ39에 대한 아버지의 연구)
(has reached clinical phase III)
(임상 3상 도달)
(And subjects are being recruited.)
(대상자를 모집하고 있습니다.)
(Can you introduce me to him?)
(나에게 그 사람을 소개해 주실 수 있나요?)
[Wen Ran, your father’s HDQ39 research has entered clinical phase III]
[원란 씨, HDQ39에 대한 아버지의 연구가 임상 3상에 도달했습니다.]
[And subjects are being recruited. Can you introduce me to him? ]
[대상자를 모집하고 있습니다. 그 사람 소개시켜 주실 수 있나요?]
[Wen Ran, your father’s HDQ39 research has entered clinical phase III]
[원란 씨, HDQ39에 대한 아버지의 연구가 임상 3상에 도달했습니다.]
[And subjects are being recruited. Can you introduce me to him? ]
[대상자를 모집하고 있습니다. 그 사람 소개시켜 주실 수 있나요?]
I just put on moisturizer.
이제 막 보습제를 발랐어요.
[Box]
[상자]
look.
바라보다.
Dr. Gu has been working overtime recently.
구 박사는 최근 야근을 하고 있습니다 .
Does He transform your pain into strength?
그분은 당신의 고통을 힘으로 바꾸고 계시나요?
Who made Dr. Gu angry?
누가 구박사를 화나게 했나요?
According to my observation,
제가 관찰한 바에 따르면,
Miss Su’s sudden departure
예고도 없이 떠난 미스. 수
Dr. Gu was angry.
구 박사님을 화나게 했어요.
He is not angry,
그 사람은 화난 게 아니고,
But it's sad.
하지만 슬프다.
Quiet!
고요!
Don't let Dr. Gu know.
구 박사에게 알리지 마세요.
I don't want to be involved in other surgeries.
나는 다른 수술에 포함되고 싶지 않습니다 .
I'm exhausted.
나 힘들어.
It's time for supper again.
야식을 먹을 시간입니다.
Do you have any late night snack?
야식 드시나요?
Try my fries.
내 감자튀김을 먹어보세요.
I've tried this before.
나는 전에 그것을 시도했다.
[He has been on duty for five consecutive days. I admire him. ]
[그는 5일 연속 근무했습니다 . 나는 그를 존경한다.]
[Cidade de Jinhai]
[시다드 드 진하이]
【Comment // Su Weian】
[코멘트 //Su Wei'an]
[Wish him a good rest. 】
[그가 편히 쉬길 바랍니다.]
(May he rest well.)
(그가 편히 쉬기를 바랍니다.)
Tia.
티아.
Are you OK?
당신은 잘 있습니다?
Help me carry the trash downstairs
이 쓰레기를 아래층으로 가져가는 것을 도와주세요
When you get off the bus.
내릴 때.
This is your honor.
이것이 당신이 받은 영예의 전부입니다.
How could they be trash?
어떻게 쓰레기가 될 수 있습니까?
this doesn't make sense
이건 말도 안 돼
In my current state.
내 현재 상태에서.
Tia.
티아.
Zhanghe Hospital has developed
장허병원이 발전했습니다.
Special drugs for Huntington’s disease,
헌팅턴병을 위한 특별한 약 ,
Already in the clinical trial stage.
이미 임상시험 중이다.
I'll sign you up tomorrow.
내일 등록하겠습니다.
I'm not a guinea pig.
나는 기니피그가 아닙니다.
I won't participate.
나는 참여하지 않을 것입니다.
How can you be a guinea pig?
어떻게 기니피그가 될 수 있나요?
drug research
약물 연구
This is the way to treat disease.
질병을 치료하는 방법입니다 .
Additionally, your disease is progressing rapidly.
게다가, 당신의 질병은 빠르게 진행되고 있습니다.
Participate in clinical research
임상 연구에 참여
This is our best option at the moment.
현재로서는 최선의 선택입니다.
My best option is to die.
나의 최선의 선택은 죽는 것입니다.
I don't want to be
난 그렇게되고 싶지 않아
a fool,
바보,
Tia.
티아.
Only dancing skeletons.
춤추는 법만 아는 해골.
You do not understand.
당신은 이해하지 못하고 있습니다.
Wei'an.
웨이안.
I would rather die than live like this.
이렇게 사느니 차라리 죽는 게 낫겠다.
How could I not understand?
어떻게 이해할 수 없습니까?
Don't tell me it's better to be alive.
사는 것이 더 낫다고 말하지 마십시오.
every second
매초
It's torture for me now.
지금은 나에게 고문이다.
Death may be the best relief.
죽음이 최고의 안식일 것입니다.
Tia.
티아.
I have lost my father.
나는 이미 아버지를 잃었습니다.
I don't want to lose my aunt, she loves me very much.
나는 나를 매우 사랑해주는 이모를 잃고 싶지 않습니다 .
do you remember
기억 나니
how did you comfort me
당신이 나를 어떻게 위로했는지
When I am anxious before the college entrance examination?
대학 입시를 앞두고 불안했을 때 ?
You said the human heart is like a harp string,
사람의 마음은 피아노선과 같다고 하셨는데,
As long as it is adjusted well,
조정되는 한,
This will be valuable.
뭔가 가치가 있을 겁니다.
The strings are still intact.
이제 문자열은 그대로 유지됩니다.
let's keep playing
계속 놀아보자,
Is he okay?
그 사람은 잘 지내?
we must believe
우리는 믿어야 해요
in medical advancements.
의료 발전에.
Huntington will one day be cured.
헌팅턴은 언젠가 치료될 것입니다.
【Zhanghe Hospital Outpatient Clinic】
[장허병원 외래진료소]
What are you looking at?
무엇을 보고 있나요?
Nothing, it seems I didn't understand it correctly.
아무것도 아닙니다. 제가 제대로 이해하지 못한 것 같습니다.
Yuncheng.
윈청.
I told you to relax.
나는 긴장을 풀라고 말했다.
Leave the experiment to my father.
실험은 아버지에게 맡기세요.
This time HDQ39
이번에는 HDQ39
It has successfully entered clinical trials.
성공적으로 임상시험에 진입했습니다.
Should I have a celebration party?
축하파티를 해야 하나?
I wish you a successful launch next year?
내년에 성공적인 출시를 기원하시겠습니까 ?
It's too early to host a reception
아직 리셉션을 열기에는 이르다
Because the third phase of research has not yet begun.
3상 연구가 아직 시작도 안 되었기 때문이다.
i see you
나는 당신을 본다
dedicated to this project,
이 프로젝트에 전념하고 있으며,
So I want you to relax.
그러므로 나는 당신이 긴장을 풀기를 바랍니다.
Okay, then I won't do that.
그럼 저는 그렇게 하지 않겠습니다.
I will do as you say.
나는 당신이 말하는 것은 무엇이든 할 것입니다.
correct.
오른쪽.
Yuncheng.
윈청.
Grandpa's birthday is coming soon.
할아버지 생신이 다가오고 있어요.
what do you think
어떻게 생각하나요
What gift should I give him?
그 사람에게 무엇을 선물로 주어야 할까요 ?
Grandpa said he didn't want to have a birthday party this year.
할아버지는 올해 생일 파티를 열고 싶지 않다고 말씀하셨어요 .
Old people don't like this.
노인들은 그런 걸 좋아하지 않아요.
Then I'll buy some fruit
그럼 과일 좀 사올게
I'm going to visit grandpa this weekend.
그리고 주말에 할아버지를 만나러 갈 거예요.
♪Darkness makes the hour hand vibrate♪
♪어둠이 시침을 진동시킨다♪
♪The noise gradually replaced the silence♪
♪소음이 점차 침묵을 대체합니다♪
♪We represent the itinerary of our meeting ♪
♪우리는 회의 일정을 대표합니다 ♪
♪Embellished with rainbows at night♪
♪밤의 무지개로 뒤덮여♪
♪E o vento no Deserto♪
♪E o Vento no Deserto♪
♪They are all our witnesses♪
♪그들은 모두 우리의 증인이었습니다♪
♪Who hasn’t experienced a reason for failure? ♪
♪실패하지 않은 사람은 누구입니까?♪
♪Looking for the one in a billion possibility♪
♪ 10억분의 1의 가능성을 찾고 있어요 ♪
♪Trapped in a city called destiny♪
♪운명이라는 도시에 갇혀버렸어♪
♪But still chasing stars♪
♪하지만 여전히 별을 쫓고 있어요♪
♪Don’t worry, I love lost people♪
♪걱정하지 마세요. 저는 잃어버린 것을 좋아해요♪
♪Raise the wine to warm the lonely soul♪
♪와인을 들고 외로운 영혼을 따뜻하게 해주세요♪
♪Please allow me to hug your slit♪
♪당신의 틈새를 안아주세요♪
♪You are as bright as a star♪
♪당신은 별처럼 빛나네요♪
♪Shine in melancholy moments♪
♪우울한 순간에도 빛난다♪
♪Darkness makes the hour hand vibrate♪
♪어둠이 시침을 진동시킨다♪
♪The noise gradually replaced the silence♪
♪소음이 점차 침묵을 대체합니다♪
♪We represent the itinerary of our meeting ♪
♪우리는 회의 일정을 대표합니다 ♪
♪Embellished with rainbows at night♪
♪밤의 무지개로 뒤덮여♪
♪E o vento no Deserto♪
♪E o Vento no Deserto♪
♪They are all our witnesses♪
♪그들은 모두 우리의 증인이었습니다♪
♪Who hasn’t experienced a reason for failure? ♪
♪실패하지 않은 사람은 누구입니까?♪
♪Looking for the one in a billion possibility♪
♪ 10억분의 1의 가능성을 찾고 있어요 ♪
♪Trapped in a city called destiny♪
♪운명이라는 도시에 갇혀버렸어♪
♪But still chasing stars♪
♪하지만 여전히 별을 쫓고 있어요♪
♪Don’t worry, I love lost people♪
♪걱정하지 마세요. 저는 잃어버린 것을 좋아해요♪
♪Raise the wine to warm the lonely soul♪
♪와인을 들고 외로운 영혼을 따뜻하게 해주세요♪
♪Please allow me to hug your slit♪
♪당신의 틈새를 안아주세요♪
♪You are as bright as a star♪
♪당신은 별처럼 빛나네요♪
♪Shine in melancholy moments♪
♪우울한 순간에도 빛난다♪